<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-25T20:29:00+02:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Susie Goodall Racing</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">DHL And Susie Goodall in Les Sables</title><link href="/news/2018/06/22/dhl-susie-goodall-les-sables/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DHL And Susie Goodall in Les Sables" /><published>2018-06-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/news/2018/06/22/dhl-susie-goodall-les-sables</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2018/06/22/dhl-susie-goodall-les-sables/">&lt;p&gt;Susie Goodall will be setting off on her solo voyage around the world as the 2018 Golden Globe Race begins in Les Sables d’Olonne, France on July 1st, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DHL Express, Susie’s Founding and Official Logistics Partner, will continue to provide support on her journey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DHL Express CEO Ken Allen: “The qualities she’ll need to take on this incredible challenge mirror the values we all share at DHL Express.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of preparation, Susie Goodall will soon embark on her non-stop solo voyage around the world as the final countdown to the Golden Globe Race 2018 is on. She is the only female and the youngest competitor amongst 19 sailors attempting to complete the journey without any outside assistance or modern equipment, recreating the conditions of the original race won by Sir Robin Knox-Johnston in 1969. DHL Express has been proud to provide logistics support for Susie throughout her preparations, including rebuilding the engine and bringing items such as solar panels and watertight doors from around the world to refurbish the vessel. They even launched a competition to choose a new name for the boat – now called DHL Starlight – that will be her home for the best part of a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a great feeling to have helped deliver Susie to the start line. We’ll all watch on with an immense amount of pride when she sets sail on July 1st. But the fact that she’ll complete the race around the time of our 50th anniversary makes it even more special for everyone at DHL,” said Ken Allen, CEO, DHL Express. “This has been her dream from a young age and her determination and perseverance to make it a reality are truly inspiring. The qualities she’ll need to take on this incredible challenge mirror the values we all share at DHL Express. She’ll need speed to win the race. She’ll need a can-do spirit in the face of adversity. She’ll need to get things right first time. And she’ll need passion to keep going when the chips are down. She may be sailing on her own, but 100,000 DHL Express employees in over 220 countries and territories worldwide are behind her all the way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the race is underway, DHL’s support will continue for example through the DHL radio network. From stations in multiple continents, DHL will contact Susie by SSB radio to keep her updated with world events, as well as exchanging messages between her and her family and friends.
“In some ways, it’s a relief to be finally starting the race,” said Susie. “It’s taken a lot of hard work and preparation just to reach this position, and I could not have done it without the support of DHL. 300 days is a long time to be alone, however knowing that DHL’s 100,000 employees are supporting me is a massive help, making me feel connected to the rest of the world even in the middle of the ocean. It’s something only a company with truly global reach can achieve.”
Susie and her fellow competitors set sail from Les Sables d’Olonne, France on July 1st. Their 48,000 km voyage will traverse the three Great Capes before returning to Les Sables d’Olonne in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep up to date with Susie’s journey, visit &lt;a class=&quot;orange&quot; href=&quot;http://discover.dhl.com&quot;&gt;discover.dhl.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Susie Goodall will be setting off on her solo voyage around the world as the 2018 Golden Globe Race begins in Les Sables d’Olonne, France on July 1st, 2018</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/dhl_les_sables.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting Ready For The Off</title><link href="/update/2018/05/18/getting-ready-for-the-off/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Ready For The Off" /><published>2018-05-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/update/2018/05/18/getting-ready-for-the-off</id><content type="html" xml:base="/update/2018/05/18/getting-ready-for-the-off/">&lt;p&gt;As the start date approaches the challenges of the race are becoming more apparent. A particular issue is going to be how to stay hydrated. Under the rules of the race, I can’t have a water maker on the boat, and I can only carry enough water for about half the time I’m away. I’ve partly solved this by taking tinned food, but most of my meals are freeze dried and I will need to collect rainwater as I go. To do this, I can attach my hoses to a drain on my sprayhood which will then fill my water tanks - and buckets to collect water as it drains off the sail work quite well. I must be one of the only people hoping for regular rain clouds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a great fan of kefir, and have been making my own long before I planned this trip. One of my pleasures will be making this daily, using the grains given to me by my mother, with UHT milk to feed it. For those of you who don’t know, kefir is similar to yoghurt, and contains all sorts of vitamins and minerals as well as a healthy dose of bacteria. I won’t be able to get fresh food once my initial supplies run out, so it’s going to be really important to find a way of keeping healthy as I go. I’m also taking a sourdough starter so I can make bread - my brother and I are going to get this underway at the weekend so it’s ready and tested by the time I leave. Having these two resources with me will be great, and will remind me every day that my family are supporting me all the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparations on the boat are coming along. This week I went round to Hamble to have the back stay fitted with some insulators which will turn it into my HF antenna. Coming back, I spent 6 hours on deck enjoying the beautiful sunny weather, and foolishly got extremely sunburnt so I was very grateful for the Weleda skin food afterwards. Despite people commenting on my windburned face when I returned, I plastered on the skin food and it took all the heat out. I also, foolishly, lifted a lot of heavy gear, and I’m now using the arnica oil to great effect. There are definitely going to be times during the nine months of the race that I will be bruised and battered, having Weleda products with me will make a great difference!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training in the lead up to the start has been quite demanding at times. On top of all the work needed to get the boat to the start line which hasn’t always been the easiest. Only 2 and a half weeks to have everything completed before I set off for Plymouth to have a final rig tune up and then to Falmouth for the Parade of Sail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to the start, but the things I will miss are beginning to take on great importance as well: not just family and friends, but simple pleasures such as my daily walk around the lakes here in the morning, bike rides and yoga on a platform that doesn’t move. And all the fresh food that I won’t have for 9 months. Despite this, I can’t wait to get going - only 6 more weeks to the start…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As the start date approaches the challenges of the race are becoming more apparent. A particular issue is going to be how to stay hydrated. Under the rules of the race, I can’t have a water maker on the boat, and I can only carry enough water for about half the time I’m away. I’ve partly solved this by taking tinned food, but most of my meals are freeze dried and I will need to collect rainwater as I go. To do this, I can attach my hoses to a drain on my sprayhood which will then fill my water tanks - and buckets to collect water as it drains off the sail work quite well. I must be one of the only people hoping for regular rain clouds!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/weleda.jpg" /></entry></feed>